Hello, English learners, and welcome back to another episode of EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一期节目。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today, with Erica, we are getting married.
今天，我和Erica要结婚了。
Well, we're not getting married.
呃，我们不是真的要结婚。
We're not, but our actors in the podcast are.
我们不是，但播客里的演员是。
That's right.
没错。
So we've got a lesson today about weddings.
所以我们今天有一节关于婚礼的课。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
A lot of the language in this lesson is about weddings and marriages.
这节课里很多语言都是关于婚礼和婚姻的。
And maybe you don't need to use this language every day, but learning this vocabulary will
也许你不需要每天使用这些语言，但学习这些词汇肯定
definitely help you understand or learn a lot more about Anglo culture.
能帮助你理解或了解更多盎格鲁文化。
Okay, great point, Marco.
说得好，Marco。
I think now we can look at our vocabulary preview.
我想现在我们可以看一下词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
So two simple words in this vocabulary preview.
这个词汇预览里有两个简单的词。
The first one is groom.
第一个是groom。
Groom.
新郎。
So who is the groom?
那么新郎是谁？
Is the man, the man that's getting married.
是男人，要结婚的男人。
Okay.
好的。
And our second word is...
我们的第二个词是……
Bride.
新娘。
And obviously, the bride is...
显然，新娘是……
The woman getting married.
要结婚的女人。
Perfect.
完美。
Now we have our bride and our groom, so it's time to listen to our dialogue the first time.
现在我们有了新娘和新郎，是时候第一次听我们的对话了。
I can't believe that Anthony is finally getting married.
真不敢相信Anthony终于要结婚了。
Yeah, well, it's about time.
是啊，也该到时候了。
He's been living with his parents for 40 years.
他和父母住了40年了。
Don't be mean.
别刻薄。
Look, here come the bridesmaids.
看，伴娘们来了。
Their dresses look beautiful.
她们的裙子看起来很漂亮。
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
那些走红毯的孩子是谁？
That's the flower girl and the ring bearer.
那是花童和戒童。
I'm pretty sure that they're the groom's niece and nephew.
我很确定他们是新郎的侄女和侄子。
Oh, they look so cute.
哦，他们看起来真可爱。
I just hope the priest makes it quick.
我只希望牧师快点结束。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
I hope the food's good at the reception.
希望婚宴上的食物好吃。
That's all you ever think about, food.
你整天就想着吃。
Oh, I think the bride's coming now.
哦，新娘要出来了。
She looks gorgeous.
她看起来美极了。
Wait, what's she doing?
等等，她在干什么？
Where is she going?
她要去哪儿？
Oh, great.
哦，太好了。
Does this mean that the reception is canceled?
这是不是意味着婚宴取消了？
Oh, Marco, that's so sad.
哦，马可，太可惜了。
Yeah.
是啊。
I know, the reception is canceled now.
我知道，婚宴取消了。
Marco, they're not getting married.
马可，他们不结婚了。
Oh, well, I mean, the best part is when you go and eat and drink at the reception.
哦，嗯，我觉得最棒的部分就是婚宴上吃吃喝喝。
Okay.
好吧。
Well, there's some great language in this dialogue.
嗯，这段对话里有些很棒的语言点。
And now, let's look at our language takeaway.
现在，我们来看看今天的语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Great.
太好了。
Our first word on the language takeaway today is, it's about time.
今天语言要点的第一个词是：it's about time。
It's about time.
终于到时候了。
So now, we are going to listen to some examples on how we use this great phrase.
现在我们来听一些例子，看看这个短语怎么用。
Example one.
例子一。
Dinner's ready.
晚饭好了。
It's about time.
终于好了。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
Example two.
例子二。
Guess what?
你猜怎么着？
I finally got a job.
我终于找到工作了。
It's about time.
总算找到了。
You've been unemployed for two years.
你已经失业两年了。
Example three.
例子三。
We're almost there.
我们快到了。
Just a couple more minutes.
再开几分钟。
It's about time.
总算快到了。
We've been driving for 12 hours.
我们已经开了12个小时了。
So this phrase means, finally.
所以这个短语的意思是，终于。
Finally, at last.
终于，最后。
We've been waiting a long time for this.
我们等这个等了很久了。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's about time.
所以，是时候了。
Great.
太好了。
Let's take a look at our second word now.
现在我们来看第二个词。
Aisle.
过道。
A-I-S-L-E.
A-I-S-L-E。
Aisle.
过道。
It's a tricky word.
这是一个容易拼错的词。
It sounds like the contraction of I will.
它听起来像“I will”的缩写。
Yeah, but it's spelled so strangely.
是啊，但拼写太奇怪了。
Right.
对。
You don't pronounce the S. The S is silent.
你不发S的音，S是不发音的。
That's true.
没错。
It's aisle.
是过道。
So what is an aisle?
那么什么是过道？
In a big room where you have a lot of chairs, that space in the middle that allows people
在一个有很多椅子的大房间里，中间那条让人
to walk through, that's the aisle.
走过去的空间，就是过道。
So the aisle is the part where you walk.
所以过道是你走的那部分。
Yes.
是的。
In a big room.
在一个大房间里。
With many chairs.
有很多椅子。
Okay.
好的。
So, in the church, the bride and groom walked on the aisle.
那么，在教堂里，新娘和新郎走过过道。
Exactly.
没错。
Great.
太好了。
Let's move to our third word.
我们来看第三个词。
This is a very tricky one.
这是一个非常容易搞混的词。
Okay.
好的。
This is a very tricky one.
这是一个非常容易搞混的词。
Okay.
好的。
So, who are the bridesmaids?
那么，谁是伴娘？
Bridesmaid.
伴娘。
Bridesmaids.
伴娘们。
So, who are the bridesmaids?
那么，谁是伴娘呢？
Or wait, maybe you should ask me that.
或者等等，也许你应该问我这个问题。
Yeah, because we don't get bridesmaids.
是啊，因为我们没有伴娘。
Okay.
好吧。
So, the bridesmaids are the women who are friends of the bride who stand next to her
伴娘就是新娘的朋友，她们站在新娘旁边
when she's getting married.
在她结婚的时候。
Usually, they're her best friends.
通常，她们是她最好的朋友。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So, we have our bridesmaids.
那么，我们有伴娘了。
Now, we have our flower girl.
现在，我们有花童了。
Flower girl.
花童。
Again, I'll explain this one.
这个我来解释。
Please, please.
请，请。
The flower girl is that cute little girl who walks down the aisle and who throws flowers.
花童就是那个可爱的小女孩，她走在过道上，撒着花。
That's the flower girl.
那就是花童。
And, with the flower girl, we have our ring bearer.
和花童一起，我们还有戒童。
Ring bearer.
戒童。
So, the ring bearer is the cute little boy who walks down the aisle carrying the...
戒童就是那个可爱的小男孩，他走在过道上，拿着……
Rings.
戒指。
Yep.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So, a lot of useful vocabulary for a wedding ceremony.
所以，婚礼上有很多有用的词汇。
That's true.
没错。
Now, let's look at our last word.
现在，我们来看最后一个词。
Gorgeous.
华丽。
Gorgeous means beautiful.
华丽的意思是美丽。
Very beautiful.
非常美丽。
Yeah.
是的。
You know, beautiful, you can only use with a woman.
你知道，beautiful 只能用于女性。
Can you use gorgeous with a woman or with a man?
gorgeous 可以用于女性还是男性？
Yes.
可以。
Gorgeous is unisex.
Gorgeous 是男女通用的。
So, both men and women are gorgeous.
所以，男人和女人都很漂亮。
Right.
对。
So, that girl is gorgeous.
所以，那个女孩很漂亮。
That guy is gorgeous.
那个男人很帅。
Right.
对。
Or you can say even this house is gorgeous.
或者你甚至可以说这栋房子很漂亮。
Okay.
好的。
So, men, women, objects.
所以，男人、女人、物品。
Yes, yes.
是的，是的。
All right.
好的。
Well, we've learned some really interesting vocabulary that will help us to understand
嗯，我们学到了一些非常有趣的词汇，这些词汇能帮助我们理解
an Anglo wedding.
一场英国婚礼。
So, why don't we listen to the dialogue slowed down?
那么，我们为什么不听一下慢速对话呢？
I can't believe that Anthony is finally getting married.
我真不敢相信安东尼终于要结婚了。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, it's about time.
嗯，也该到时候了。
He's been living with his parents for 40 years.
他已经和他父母住了40年了。
Don't be mean.
别刻薄。
Look, here come the bridesmaids.
看，伴娘们来了。
Their dresses look beautiful.
她们的裙子看起来很漂亮。
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
那些走红毯的孩子是谁？
That's the flower girl and the ring bearer.
那是花童和戒童。
I'm pretty sure they're the groom's niece and nephew.
我很确定他们是新郎的侄女和侄子。
Oh, they look so cute.
哦，他们看起来真可爱。
I just hope the priest makes it quick.
我只希望牧师快点。
I'm starving.
我饿坏了。
I hope the food's good at the reception.
我希望婚宴上的食物好吃。
That's all you ever think about, food.
你整天就想这个，食物。
Oh, I think the bride's coming now.
哦，我想新娘现在来了。
She looks gorgeous.
她看起来美极了。
Wait, what's she doing?
等等，她在干什么？
Where's she going?
她要去哪儿？
Oh, great.
哦，太好了。
Does this mean that the reception is canceled?
这是不是意味着婚宴取消了？
Now in this dialogue, we have a word that many students often make mistakes on.
在这个对话中，有一个词很多学生经常犯错。
So this is a word that causes a lot of problems.
所以这是一个引起很多问题的词。
Yes, the word marry.
是的，marry这个词。
Marry.
Marry。
Marry, right?
Marry，对吧？
So we are going to listen now to some common mistakes on how English learners use this
所以我们现在要听一些英语学习者在使用这个词时常犯的错误。
word.
单词。
Right, so these are wrong examples.
对，所以这些是错误例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Honey, let's marry.
亲爱的，我们结婚吧。
Example two.
例子二。
We married four years ago.
我们四年前结婚了。
Example three.
例子三。
When I marry, I want a huge wedding.
我结婚时，想要一个盛大的婚礼。
These are great examples of mistakes students make with the word marry.
这些都是学生使用“结婚”这个词时犯的典型错误。
They're missing a word.
它们漏了一个词。
Let's listen to these right examples to see what word is missing.
让我们听听这些正确的例子，看看漏了哪个词。
Example one.
例子一。
Honey, let's get married.
亲爱的，我们结婚吧。
Example two.
例子二。
We got married four years ago.
我们四年前结婚了。
Example three.
例子三。
When I get married, I want a huge wedding.
我结婚时，想要一个盛大的婚礼。
Great, so we can see that when we use the word marry, we say to get married.
太好了，所以我们可以看到，当我们使用“结婚”这个词时，我们说“结婚”。
Exactly right.
完全正确。
Get married.
结婚。
To get married, right?
结婚，对吧？
Okay, don't forget that.
好的，别忘了。
Yes.
是的。
Get married.
结婚。
I will get married.
我会结婚。
We got married.
我们结婚了。
Right.
对。
So now you know exactly how to use this word.
所以现在你确切知道如何使用这个词了。
We are ready to listen to our dialogue again for a third time and this time it's going
我们准备第三次听对话，这次将是
to be at a normal speed.
正常语速。
I can't believe that Anthony is finally getting married.
真不敢相信安东尼终于要结婚了。
Yeah, well, it's about time.
是啊，也该到时候了。
He's been living with his parents for 40 years.
他和父母住了40年了。
Don't be mean.
别刻薄。
Look, here come the bridesmaids.
看，伴娘们来了。
Their dresses look beautiful.
她们的裙子看起来很漂亮。
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
那些走红毯的孩子是谁？
That's the flower girl and the rain bearer.
那是花童和戒童。
I'm pretty sure that they're the groom's niece and nephew.
我很确定他们是新郎的侄女和侄子。
Oh, they look so cute.
哦，他们看起来真可爱。
I just hope the priest makes it quick.
我只希望牧师快点结束。
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
I hope the food's good at the reception.
希望婚宴上的食物好吃。
That's all you ever think about, food.
你整天就只想着吃。
Oh, I think the bride's coming now.
哦，我觉得新娘来了。
She looks gorgeous.
她看起来美极了。
Wait, what's she doing?
等等，她在干什么？
Where is she going?
她要去哪儿？
So great.
太好了。
Does this mean that the reception is canceled?
这是不是意味着婚宴取消了？
Okay, well, I'm going to be honest with you.
好吧，我跟你说实话。
I don't know too much about marriages because, first of all, I'm not married and I've never
我对婚礼不太了解，因为首先，我没结过婚，而且我也没
really been to many marriages.
怎么参加过婚礼。
So, Erica, some questions for you.
那么，Erica，问你几个问题。
Okay.
好的。
What are these bridesmaids do?
这些伴娘是做什么的？
I mean, what are they about?
我是说，她们是干嘛的？
What do the bridesmaids do?
伴娘是做什么的？
Yeah, what are they doing there?
是啊，她们在那儿干什么？
Well, like I said earlier, the bridesmaids are the friends of the bride.
嗯，就像我之前说的，伴娘是新娘的朋友。
But the most important people, besides the bride and groom, are the best man and the
但除了新娘和新郎，最重要的人是伴郎和
maid of honor.
伴娘。
Okay.
好的。
And what do they do there in the ceremony?
那他们在仪式上做什么？
Well, what they do is they sign the marriage license.
他们要做的是在结婚证上签字。
Okay.
好的。
So they're like witnesses.
所以他们就像证人。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So, but wait a minute.
但是，等等。
They sign the marriage license there in the church?
他们在教堂里签结婚证？
Yeah, of course.
是啊，当然。
Right inside the church, you sign the marriage license.
就在教堂里面，签结婚证。
Wow, that's strange because, from what I know, in other countries, usually you will sign
哇，这很奇怪，因为据我所知，在其他国家，通常是在
the marriage license before the ceremony.
仪式之前签结婚证。
So you get married twice?
所以你们要结两次婚？
Yeah, you have like the civil marriage and then you have like the church wedding or whatever.
是啊，先有民事婚姻，然后有教堂婚礼之类的。
That's so complicated.
真复杂。
Well, yeah, I mean, the church wedding is just the ceremony.
嗯，是啊，教堂婚礼只是仪式。
It's not really anything official.
并不是什么正式的东西。
Oh, in Canada, it's the official part as well.
哦，在加拿大，这也是正式的部分。
I guess maybe you're just more efficient.
我想也许你只是效率更高。
Maybe.
也许吧。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, this is a really fascinating, a really interesting subject, isn't it?
嗯，这真是一个引人入胜、非常有趣的话题，不是吗？
Yeah, because there's so many countries that have different marriage ceremonies.
是啊，因为有很多国家有不同的婚礼仪式。
I know that marriages in India last around seven days.
我知道印度的婚礼会持续大约七天。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
I want to know more about how our users get married in their country.
我想了解更多关于我们的用户在自己的国家是如何结婚的。
Yeah.
是啊。
So please go to our website at EnglishPod.com and tell us how you get married in your countries.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，告诉我们你们在自己的国家是如何结婚的。
Yeah, I can't wait to hear your stories.
是啊，我等不及要听你们的故事了。
Yeah, it should be interesting, right?
是啊，应该会很有趣，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
Well, everyone, thanks for listening and until next time, goodbye.
好了，各位，感谢收听，下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
再见。